<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lifestyle on David Nazareth</title>
    <link>/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lifestyle on David Nazareth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make our Planet Great Again!</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog4/</guid>
      <description>While it is true that the earth’s temperature has changed a lot over the course of its 4.5-billion-year history, the pace of the warming that we are seeing in the recent past is unprecedented. In spite of many significant warning signs, many people choose to deny the fact that man-made climate change is an issue that needs to be addressed urgently if we want to save millions of species from the harsh conditions that will arise if we allow 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Death Rate</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog3/</guid>
      <description>I will now attempt to visualise the death rate of patients from different age groups and genders based on whether they had pre-existing medical conditions or not and on whether they were admitted into the ICU or not. The CDC Covid-19 Case Surveillance Data(https://data.cdc.gov/Case-Surveillance/COVID-19-Case-Surveillance-Public-Use-Data/vbim-akqf) has de-identified patient data on cases recorded in the United States. There are well over 3 million records so I will use the vroom package to load it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP Components</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog2/</guid>
      <description>The main components of gross domestic product, GDP are personal consumption (C), business investment (I), government spending (G) and net exports (exports - imports). You can read more about GDP and the different approaches in calculating at the Wikipedia GDP page.
The GDP data we will look at is from the United Nations’ National Accounts Main Aggregates Database, which contains estimates of total GDP and its components for all countries from 1970 to today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TfL Bike Rentals</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog1/</guid>
      <description>The pandemic has impacted how people move in many of the world’s largest cities. People are working and studying from home and do not move about as much as they used to. The usage of public transport has gone down drastically as the public explore safer options to move about like personal vehicles and cycles. In this analysis, I will attempt to explore how the pandemic has affected the monthly and weekly rentals of Santander cycles in London by comparing it with the expected monthly rentals calculated using data on bike rentals over the last 5 years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>