<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Nazareth</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David Nazareth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TfL Rentals</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog1/</guid>
      <description>The London data store (https://data.london.gov.uk/dataset/number-bicycle-hires) provides us with data on the total number of Santander cycles hired by day, month and year since the scheme started on 30th July 2010. We can access the latest data from the site and store it in a temporary excel file. We will then clean the column names using clean_names() from the janitor package and extract the year, month and day from the day column using functions from the lubridate package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP Components</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog6/</guid>
      <description>The main components of gross domestic product, GDP are personal consumption (C), business investment (I), government spending (G) and net exports (exports - imports). You can read more about GDP and the different approaches in calculating at the Wikipedia GDP page.
The GDP data we will look at is from the United Nations’ National Accounts Main Aggregates Database, which contains estimates of total GDP and its components for all countries from 1970 to today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>